welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we call hear and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
Tyson Wagner you had a question about
queueing on yes thank you
q and on has this in my personal
experience what I see in my community
that's kind of captivating almost
seductive sensational thing going on in
the way it captures people's attention
and I'm wondering like what can we learn
about good distributed collective
intelligence from q and on and then what
should we be most cautious of when
looking at that and learning from that
that's a really good question thank you
by the way a bold question because as
you know even I think using the letter Q
these days tended to get you thrown in
jail so let's see let's think about that
so first off let's recognize that I
think the answer to the first part is a
lot I think it's naive beyond
comprehension to not recognize it that
was a very powerful valuable experience
from which we can learn a lot so what
are the some of the things that showed
up if you think about it and I was
watching it very closely for a long time
so some of the things that showed up I
would say are like cardinal virtues it's
a deep stuff that frankly has been part
of cold any culture that's worth of
for a long time
the phrase is like where we go one we go
all notions like own your mistakes
notions like take responsibility for
actually digging take personal
responsibility for perceiving reality
think bigger don't be trapped in
existing ideological frameworks of what
isn't what is not be aware the fact that
this information and disinformation is
everywhere so don't stick to any
particular point of view and assume that
that is authoritative
hope community connecting with each
other helping each other now this like
you know in some sense it isn't that
complicated just to take a look at at
the mythopoetic archetypes of what
virtue and heroism and wholesomeness
have always looked like and do that and
to the degree to which the Q community
found that and upregulated that that is
the strong positive virtues that are in
fact in that community all right let's
go to the opposite direction it's weird
because it seems to hold both
simultaneously which is kind of an
interesting thing well there's a certain
mania well there's a certain manic
psychotic Sensibility a we live in a
psychotic age and we live in a psychotic
age because we all have the capacity to
interact with far more
information about reality then a our
minds can handle and far less
information about reality than be
actually tells us much about reality so
in an environment we can tell really
awesome stories we can weave together
narratives that sort of hold the
information that we've been able to
gather and hold into something like a
coherent story and then we try to
fact-check that by actually doing more
information this is what I think where
the acute phenomena has is one of his
biggest gaps is that it's so bound to
the virtual and it's so capable I've
been researching things at the virtual
but then tries to draw conjectures on
the basis inference and hypothesis and
models of nature and and models about
what the underlying the axiomatic
structures of reality are so if you
think that I don't know let's go with
something
you think there's an organization called
Rizvi 2 verse which is tied to the Saudi
royal family and they have certain
capacities and agendas then you can use
that assumption complex about which you
have no in reality to explain a very
large number of phenomena now you're
gonna get a whole bunch of anomalous
phenomena around that but you're gonna
pretend to ignore the anomalous
phenomena be really happy about the
thing that's inside your explanatory
framework which is you say the key
phenomenon gives us bas relief on the
weakness of the paradigmatic mind . it
tended to be psychotic and manic and to
be self was the true bias towards its
own self referentiality
and of course we also seen a tendency a
strong tendency although not necessarily
a overwhelming tendency to engage in the
exact opposite of responsibility to
externalize to hope that someone else is
in charge and will in fact take care of
us and I believe that is also
unfortunate at the end of the day false
which is to say only this to the degree
which there are people who are in
positions of power authority
responsibility who have our best
interest in mind
great awesome if we take responsibility
for ourselves with complete integrity
then their interest in our interests
would be completely aligned so we don't
need to worry about whether they're
there or not but to the degree to which
we alienate ourselves from our own
agency just sort of step back and really
hope they're doing a good job and become
cheerleaders or fans in a sporting event
and they're the team on the field and
we're the guys the butts in the seats
we've done exactly the wrong thing
I'm sure there's more but that's that's
enough for now I reckon